

# **LOVE TYAGI**

Data Science Leader, making decision-making smarter, efficient and better than ever before.

ABOUT ME

Highly efficient results driven and problem solving attitude to effectively develop, manage, and control relationships between the company and its clients. Having a strong mathematical background and experience in AI and Data Science for around 10 years has helped me understanding clients problems, vision, and objective and providing solutions which helps in making efficient, smart and intelligent decision making. Passion for solving tough problems and ability to work with teams all across the world has enabled me and my teams delivering State of the art AI solutions for clients in the areas of Statistics, Forecasting, Natural language processing and Image processing.



# WORK EXPERIENCE

# DATA SCIENCE DELIVERY LEAD ( PORTFOLIO ~3MN-4MN . YEAR)

ZS ASSOCAITES, LOS ANGLES, USA MAR-2018 - PRESENT

- Disrupting old sales force targeting methodology using AI solution to enable dynamic targeting and connecting sales reps with best possible physicians on every day basis. Tech Used - Spark framework, RNN, Xgboost, DeepAR, Python
- Developed platform for expediting research and drug development for some of the world Bio Tech companies. Tech Used - SOTA NLP frameworks, Bio-Bert, Transfer learning,
- Helped client solving long standing problem of patients drop out during clinical trials using clinical data and improving success of enrollments and expediting finishing clinical trials. Tech Used - Time Series Analysis, Python
- Helped developing solution for finding duplicate clinical studies happening all across the globe to help client learn from the previous experiments made by other companies. Tech Used - Similarity Based Algorithms, GANs, Clustering, Python.
- Helped Designing Next Best Engagement for physicians all across USA based upon channel data, call response data, ads data. Tech Used - Genetic Algorithms, clustering,
- Epidemiologica Modeling for understanding the impact of Covid on currently ongoing clinical trials for healthcare giants and helped them running their day to day operations in regards to trials. Tech Used - SIER, SIR, Logistic Growth, R and Python.

• Build Email Spamming systems for a company so that they can never miss out on critical

• Build anomaly based time series models for finding anomalies in production rates for

Texas Instruments (one of the top 10 semi conductor companies in the world).

• Managing overall portfolio of \$3mn -\$4mn per year with clients all across USA

emails and don't miss out on the important

# **DATA SCIENTIST**

MOSAIC ATM, USA JULY-2017 - DEC -2017

## **RESEARCH ANALYST**

UNITED HEALTH GROUP, INDIA MAY-2013 - MAY-2016

- Helped building claims fraud detection systems for one of the fortune 50 companies in the world. System has the capacity to separate out fraudulent claims automatically and stoped the processing for those claims, saving around millions of dollars every year. Tech Used - Anomaly detection, logistic classifier, Using EHR data, Big Data, Python
  - Helped building a pipeline for analytics services after absorbing data from different big data sources. Tech Used - Big Data, Logistic Modeling, R, Python.
  - Build various Executive Dashboards using best visualization tools like Tableau

# DATA AND BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE ENGG

**BIRLASOFT PVT LTD, INDIA** 2013-04 - 2016-06

- Build naive machine learning models and supported already built models in production
- Running month/month evaluation metrics for various models and discuss the model performance with business.
- Taking care of training data, model and data drift during modeling operations support
- Ran various statistical tests for accessing data quality, data anomalies, data drift, initial

## **EDUCATION**

# MASTER IN DATA SCIENCE ( MAJOR MACHINE LEARNING AND STATISTICS)

GEORGE WASHINGTON UNIVERSTIY, VIRGINIA, USA

JULY- 2016 - DEC -2017

**BACHELOR IN TECHNOLOGY, E&C** 

JAMIA MILLIA ISLAMIA 2006 - 2010

CGPA -3.90/4

CGPA -8.77/10



# **CORE COMPETENCIES**

## AI FRAMEWORKS

Have great hands on knowledge of mostly used AI frameworks like Tensorflow, Pytorch, NLP, Conv Nets, GANs

## **STATISTICS**

Traditional Heavy statistical knowledge, Probability distributions, hypothesis testing, A/B testing etc.

## MACHINE LEARNING

Have vast experience in traditional ML Modeling like linear regression, logistic regression, Forest based algorithms, Boosting machines, statistical testing, time series analysis (Arima etc)

# BUILDING BENEFICIAL RELATIONSHIPS AND CLIENT MANAGEMENT

Great Strategic and Business consulting skills, skill of maintaining a very healthy and long term relationship with multiple clients all across USA, specially with Healthcare Giants.

# TEAM MANAGEMENT



# **CERTIFICAITONS**

## **DEEP LEARNING SPECIALIZATION**

**COURSERA** 

2017

Deep learning AI specialization certified by Coursera. Courses completed a power pack knowledge and here is the link

https://coursera.org/share/4d1d1653b364924f5c0bbf685127e496

- Deep Learning and Neural Networks
- Conv Nets
- Sequence Models
- NLP
- Hyper Tuning and Structuring Machine learning projects.

# ALGORITHIMIC THINKING

RICE UNIVERSITY

2019

https://coursera.org/share/430ad8b82e23d4d6dfeb63581f59ad3b

# **BAYESIAN STATISTICS**

**COURSERA** 2018

Bayesian Regression and other concepts involving use of bayesian methods in day to day modeling process, specially the process which involve prior business knowledge

https://coursera.org/share/72567124905b255b9bcd82d32ef28cec

# GOOGLE CLOUD FUNDAMENTALS FOR BIG DATA AND ML

Cloud Fundamentals which stay true in All cloud settings like Amazon, Azure and Google.

https://coursera.org/share/41d0cbbc587c80732fa12ac9152a7009

# **R PROGRAMMING**

JOHN HOPKINS, USA 2016

Certified R Programmer